<metadata>
	<NPS_Info>
		<MetaPurp>NPS </MetaPurp>
		<NPS_Unit>
			<UnitCode>GRSM </UnitCode>
			<UnitType>Park </UnitType>
		</NPS_Unit>
		<DatStore>
			<Category>Biology </Category>
			<DSteward>
				<cntinfo>
					<cntperp>
						<cntper>Thomas Colson</cntper>
					</cntperp>
					<cntaddr>
						<addrtype>mailing and physical </addrtype>
						<address>107 Park HQ Road </address>
						<city>Gatlinburg </city>
						<state>TN </state>
						<postal>37783  </postal>
						<country>US </country>
					</cntaddr>
					<cntvoice>(865)436-1701 </cntvoice>
					<cntemail>thomas_colson@nps.gov </cntemail>
					<hours>0700-1630 </hours>
					<cntinst>email only </cntinst>
				</cntinfo>
			</DSteward>
		</DatStore>
	</NPS_Info>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>National Park Service, Great Smoky Mountains National Park </origin>
				<pubdate>20141201 </pubdate>
				<title>Great Smoky Mountains National Park Bufo americanus (American toad) presence observations. </title>
				<othercit>ATBI </othercit>
				<onlink>Default value. </onlink>
				<geoform xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">vector digital data</geoform>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>This is a vector point file showing Bufo americanus (American toad) presence observations at Great Smoky Mountains National Park (GRSM). </abstract>
			<purpose>To show the location of Bufo americanus (American toad) presence observations at Great Smoky Mountains National Park. The intended use of all data in the park's GIS library is to support diverse park activities including planning, management, maintenance, research, and interpretation.</purpose>
			<supplinf>The native format of these data may have been configured to render and display in the Great Smoky Mountains National Park Topographic Map Series at 1:24,000-scale. Most users may find this symbology difficult to use. Users should consult their GIS software documentation for instructions on altering the symbology of these data for display in propiertary applications. </supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate/>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>In work</progress>
			<update>As needed</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-83.948090</westbc>
				<eastbc>-83.040400</eastbc>
				<northbc>35.787991</northbc>
				<southbc>35.432229</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>National Park Service Theme Category Thesaurus</themekt>
				<themekey>Biology </themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>biota </themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing</themekt>
				<themekey>National Standards for Spatial Digital Accuracy (NSSDA)</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>Counties and County Equivalents of the States of the United States and the District of Columbia (FIPS Pub 6-3)</placekt>
				<placekey>Swain County, North Carolina</placekey>
				<placekey>Haywood County, North Carolina</placekey>
				<placekey>Graham County, North Carolina</placekey>
				<placekey>Cocke County, Tennessee</placekey>
				<placekey>Sevier County, Tennessee</placekey>
				<placekey>Blount County, Tennessee</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>USGS Topographic Map Names Data Base</placekt>
				<placekey>BLOCKHOUSE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>BRYSON CITY, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>BUNCHES BALD, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>CADES COVE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>CALDERWOOD, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>CLINGMANS DOME, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>COVE CREEK GAP, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>DELLWOOD, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>FINES CREEK, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>FONTANA DAM, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>GATLINBURG, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>HARTFORD, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>JONES COVE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>KINZEL SPRINGS, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>LUFTEE KNOB, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>MOUNT GUYOT, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>MOUNT LE CONTE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>NOLAND CREEK, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>PIGEON FORGE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>RICHARDSON COVE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>SILERS BALD, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>SMOKEMONT, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>TALLASSEE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>TAPOCO, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>THUNDERHEAD MOUNTAIN, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>TUSKEEGEE, NC</placekey>
				<placekey>WATERVILLE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>WEAR COVE, TN</placekey>
				<placekey>WHITTIER, NC</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>National Park System Unit Code Thesaurus</placekt>
				<placekey>GRSM</placekey>
				<placekey>NRIM</placekey>
				<placekey>SERO</placekey>
				<placekey>APHN</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>National Park System Unit Name Thesaurus</placekt>
				<placekey>Great Smoky Mountains National Park</placekey>
				<placekey>Natural Resource Inventory and Monitoring Program</placekey>
				<placekey>Southeast Region</placekey>
				<placekey>Appalachian Highlands Network</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
				<placekey>North Carolina</placekey>
				<placekey>Tennessee</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the identification of the States, the District of Columbia and the outlying areas of the United States, and associated areas (Federal Information Processing Standard 5-2): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>
				<placekey>NC</placekey>
				<placekey>TN</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1995, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions, Federal Information Processing Standard 10-4,): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>
				<placekey>US</placekey>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
				<placekey>U.S.</placekey>
				<placekey>USA</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">
				<tempkt>None</tempkt>
				<tempkey>Current</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>Commercial entities using these data for Location Based Service, map publication, or other redistributions of these data should read the contents of this metadata. Improper application of these data by failure to do so could result in inappropriate use of these data, includling, but not limited to, errors in navigation resulting in hazardous conditions, for which the National Park Service is not liable. If a trail is not depicted within these data, entities redistributing these data may not produce applications and publications that display such trails, not communicate or advise travel or navigation on a trail not depicted in these data. Travel on a trail not depicted in these data is considered "Back Country Off-Trail" travel, and not encouraged or endorsed by the National Park Service. </useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>National Park Service</cntorg>
					<cntper>Thomas Colson</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
					<address>107 Park HQ Road</address>
					<city>Gatlinburg</city>
					<state>TN</state>
					<postal>37873</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(865)436-1701</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>thomas_colson@nps.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>0800-1700</hours>
				<cntinst>email only</cntinst>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<secinfo xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">
			<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
		</secinfo>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>Attribute accuracy was tested by manual comparison of the source with hard copy plots and/or symbolized display of the map data on an interactive computer graphic system. Selected attributes that cannot be visually verified on plots or on screen are interactively queried and verified on screen. In addition, the attributes are tested against a master set of valid attributes. All attribute data conform to the attribute codes in the signed classification and correlation document and amendment(s). Subject-matter experts for these data where also consulted and reviewed the fitness of these data when applied to the park mission of visitor experience and resource protection.</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>Polygons intersecting neatlines are closed along their border. Segments making up the outer and inner boundaries of a polygon tie end-to-end to completely enclose the area. Line segments are a set of sequentially numbered coordinate pairs. No duplicate features exist nor duplicate points in a data string. Intersecting lines are separated into individual line segments at the point of intersection. Point data are represented by two sets of coordinate pairs, each with the same coordinate values. All nodes are represented by a single coordinate pair which indicates the beginning or end of a line segment. The neatline is generated by connecting the four corners of the digital file, as established during initialization of the digital file. All data crossing the neatline are clipped to the neatline and data within a specified tolerance of the neatline are snapped to the neatline.</logic>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>
These data meet United States National Map Accuracy Standards for Horizontal data, which are as follows: For maps on publication scales larger than 1:20,000, not more than 10 percent of the points tested shall be in error by more than 1/30 inch, measured on the publication scale; for maps on publication scales of 1:20,000 or smaller, 1/50 inch. These limits of accuracy shall apply in all cases to positions of well-defined points only. Well-defined points are those that are easily visible or recoverable on the ground, such as the following: monuments or markers, such as bench marks, property boundary monuments; intersections of roads, railroads, etc.; corners of large buildings or structures (or center points of small buildings); etc. In general what is well defined will be determined by what is plottable on the scale of the map within 1/100 inch. Thus while the intersection of two road or property lines meeting at right angles would come within a sensible interpretation, identification of the intersection of such lines meeting at an acute angle would obviously not be practicable within 1/100 inch. Similarly, features not identifiable upon the ground within close limits are not to be considered as test points within the limits quoted, even though their positions may be scaled closely upon the map. In this class would come timber lines, soil boundaries, etc.

In order to determine if these data meet United States National Map Accuracy Standard, location accuracy checks were performed either by compating mapped locations to GPS assesment, where GPS standard meet or exceede standars specified in FGDC-STD-007.2-1998 Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standards Part 2: Standards for Geodetic Networks and FGDC-STD-007.3-1998 Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standards Part 3: National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy; or comparing mapped location to aerial photography that meets or exceedes FGDC-STD-008-1999 Content Standards for Digital Orthoimagery.
				</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
			<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>When vertical measurements are used to supplement measurements, these data meet United States National Map Accuracy Standards for Vertical data, which are as follows: Vertical accuracy, as applied to contour maps on all publication scales, shall be such that not more than 10 percent of the elevations tested shall be in error more than one-half the contour interval. In checking elevations taken from the map, the apparent vertical error may be decreased by assuming a horizontal displacement within the permissible horizontal error for a map of that scale. Vertical measurements may have been used in these data to calculate area, length, or vertical (Z) coordinates.</vertaccr>
			</vertacc>
		</posacc>
		<cloud>0%</cloud>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">
		<direct>Vector</direct>
	</spdoinfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Thomas Colson</cntper>
					<cntorg>National Park Service</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
					<address>107 Park HQ Road</address>
					<city>Gatlinburg</city>
					<state>TN</state>
					<postal>37873</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(865)436-1701</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>thomas_colson@nps.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>0800-1700</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<distliab>The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on computer systems at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<fees>None</fees>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>geojson</formname>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>https://github.com/nationalparkservice/npmap-species/blob/master/atbirecords/Geojsons/Amphibia/Bufo_americanus.geojson</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
						<oncomp>http://geojson.org/geojson-spec.html</oncomp>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Thomas Colson</cntper>
					<cntorg>National Park Service</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>107 Park Headquarters Rd.</address>
					<city>Gatlinburg</city>
					<state>Tennessee</state>
					<postal>37738</postal>
					<country>United States</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(865)436-1701</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>GRSM_Resource_Management@nps.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>0800-1730 EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<distliab>The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on computer systems at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formspec xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">Compressed File Geodatabase</formspec>
					<filedec xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">RAR</filedec>
				</digtinfo>
			</digform>
			<fees>None</fees>
			<ordering xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">Users requesting these data should consult National Park Service: Thomas Colson. 2013. Core Base Data, Great Smoky Mountains National Park. Geodatabase-2202742 for download instructions.</ordering>
		</stdorder>
		<custom xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">Requestors may send portable media (Portable hard drive, blank digital optical media) to the contact listed in this record. All delivered materials must include return postage or shipping labels. The National Park Service is unable to return portable media delivered to the contact location that is not accompanied by return shipping. The National Park Service shall not be held liable for damage caused to portable media during shipping to or from the contact location.</custom>
		<availabl xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20130826</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
		</availabl>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20141201 </metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Thomas Colson</cntper>
					<cntorg>National Park Service</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
					<address>107 Park HQ Road</address>
					<city>Gatlinburg</city>
					<state>TN</state>
					<postal>37873</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(865)436-1701</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>thomas_colson@nps.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>0800-1700</hours>
				<cntinst>email only</cntinst>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://nrdata.nps.gov/profiles/NPS_Profile.xml</onlink>
			<metprof>NPS NR and GIS Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<mettc xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">local time</mettc>
	</metainfo>
</metadata>
